bluelivingideas.com 2017-10-08

# Privacy Policy - Blue Living Ideas

**BlueLivingIdeas Privacy Policy**  
Date Last Revised: December 15 2016

**[Contact us](mailto:hello@bluelivingideas.com) if you have any questions or concerns.**

This privacy policy describes our policies on the collection, use, and disclosure of your information in connection with your use of our website, emails, and mobile applications (“Site”) and how we use that information in connection with our service offered through the Site (the “Service”). The terms “we”, “us”, “BlueLivingIdeas”, “BlueLivingIdeas.com” refer to BlueLivingIdeas.

When you use the Site, you consent to our collection, use, and disclosure of your information as described in this Privacy Policy. BlueLivingIdeas is committed to maintaining the confidentiality, integrity and security of any personal identity information about our users. The information addressed in this Privacy Policy includes “Personal Information,” which is information about you that is personally identifiable such as your full name, physical address or email address, telephone and fax number as well as “Non-Identifiable Information,” which is non-public information that may be associated with or linked to a specific BlueLivingIdeas account but does not by itself permit the identification of individual persons (e.g., demographic, interest, or site usage information). This Privacy Policy does not pertain to any information that is publicly available on or through BlueLivingIdeas.

BlueLivingIdeas stresses its privacy and security standards to guard against identity theft and provide security for your Personal Information. We regularly re-evaluate our privacy and security policies and adapt them as necessary to deal with new challenges.

**Your Privacy is not for sale**

BlueLivingIdeas uses and discloses your Personal Information as follows:

  * to analyze site usage and improve the Service and Site;
  * to deliver to you any administrative notices and communications relevant to your use of the Service;
  * to fulfill your requests for certain products and services;
  * for market research, project planning, troubleshooting problems, detecting and
  * protecting against error, fraud or other criminal activity;
  * to third parties that provide services to BlueLivingIdeas;
  * to enforce BlueLivingIdeas’s Terms of Use; and
  * as otherwise set forth in this Privacy Policy.

**We limit the collection and use of your information**

In general, we collect both Personal Information and Non-Identifiable Information that you submit voluntarily to BlueLivingIdeas. We collect information that you submit during the process of creating or editing your account and user profile on the Site. For example, the registration and login process requires you to provide us with your name, email address, and password (collectively “Registration Information”).

We may also request Non-Identifiable Information including year of birth, gender, and other demographic information. We also collect information from content that you submit during your use of the Site, such as comments or feedback, and other information you chose to submit, including information from other social networks that you choose to link to your account.

From time to time we may request other Personal Information to provide you with other benefits of the Service. In all such instances, you will be given the opportunity to provide or to decline to provide that information, and it will be used only for the stated purpose. BlueLivingIdeas may make anonymous or aggregate Personal Information and disclose such data in a non-personally identifiable in combination with Non-Identifiable Information to:

**Advertisers and other third parties for their marketing and promotional purposes**

Organizations approved by BlueLivingIdeas that conduct research into consumer habits and lifestyle. Such information does not identify you individually.

Access to your Registration Information, Account Credentials, Account Information and any other Personal Information you provide is restricted and used in accordance with internal procedures and safeguard governing access, in order to operate, develop or improve the Service. Employees may be subject to discipline, including termination and criminal prosecution, if they fail to meet these obligations. We may also use third party vendors or service providers to help us provide the Service to you, such as sending email messages on our behalf or hosting and operating a particular feature or functionality of the Service. Our contracts with these third parties outline the appropriate use and handling of your information and prohibit them from using any of your Personal Information for purposes unrelated to the product or service they’re providing. We require such third parties to maintain the confidentiality of the information we provide to them.

In general, both the Personal Information and Non-Identifiable Information you submit to us is used to provide you access to BlueLivingIdeas, to improve BlueLivingIdeas, to better tailor the features, performance, and support of BlueLivingIdeas and to offer you additional information, opportunities, promotions and functionality from us, our partners or our advertisers. For example, we may use and display your full name and email address when you send an email notification to a friend through BlueLivingIdeas or the social network from which you have connected to BlueLivingIdeas (such as in an invitation, or when sharing your content).

This Privacy Policy does not limit our use or disclosure of Non-Identifiable Information in any way, and we reserve the right to use and disclose Non-Identifiable Information to our partners, advertisers and other third parties at our discretion. Specifically, we may use any of the Non-Identifiable Information you provide or that we collect from you or third parties to assist us in recommending content or connections, and we may disclose Non-Identifiable Information to third parties who assist us in delivering you more relevant advertising and content.

**Third Party Vendors**

Third party vendors, including Google, use cookies to serve ads based on a user’s prior visits to your website or other websites.

Google’s use of advertising cookies enables it and its partners to serve ads to your users based on their visit to your sites and/or other sites on the Internet.

Users may opt out of personalized advertising by visiting [Ads Settings.](https://www.google.com/settings/ads)

In addition to Google ads, our sites use other vendors for advertisements.

  * Other vendors may include Sortable, Monetize More, AOL and others.
  * You may visit the above websites to opt out of the use of cookies for personalized advertising (if the vendor or ad network offers this capability). Alternatively, you can opt out of some third-party vendors’ uses of cookies for personalized advertising by visiting [AboutAds](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/).

If your Registration Information changes during your subscription to BlueLivingIdeas, you may update it any time via the Service.

**Online session information collection and use improves your experience**

When you visit BlueLivingIdeas.com, we may collect technical and navigational information, such as computer browser type, Internet protocol address, operating system, the source that directed you to our site, pages visited, and average time spent on our Site. This information is gathered to make BlueLivingIdeas more useful to you and may be used, for example, to alert you to software compatibility issues, or it may be analyzed to improve our Web design and functionality.

“Cookies” are alphanumeric identifiers in the form of text files that are inserted and stored by your Web browser on your computer’s hard drive. BlueLivingIdeas may set and access cookies on your computer to track and store preferential information about you. BlueLivingIdeas may gather information about you through cookie technology. For example, BlueLivingIdeas may assign a cookie to you, to limit the amount of times you see a particular feature or to help better determine how to serve to you. Please note that most Internet browsers will allow you to stop cookies from being stored on your computer and to delete cookies stored on your computer. If you choose to eliminate cookies, the full functionality of the Service may be impaired for you.

Web beacons are images embedded in a Web page or email for the purpose of measuring and analyzing site usage and activity. BlueLivingIdeas or third party service providers acting on our behalf, may use Web beacons to help us analyze Site usage and improve the Service.

An “Internet protocol address” or “IP address” is a number automatically assigned to your computer when you use the Internet. In some cases your IP address stays the same from browser session to session; however if you use a consumer Internet access provider, your IP address probably varies from session to session. We, or our service providers, may track your IP address when you access BlueLivingIdeas.

We may use third party service providers to help us analyze certain online activities. For example, these service providers may help us measure the performance of our online campaigns, analyze visitor activity on BlueLivingIdeas.com, or track conversions. We may permit these service providers to use cookies and other technologies to perform these services for BlueLivingIdeas. We do not share any Personal Information about our customers with these third party service providers, and these service providers do not collect such information on our behalf.

**Blogs and other Forums on BlueLivingIdeas.com**

If you use a forum, blog or otherwise post public content on our Site, you should be aware that any information you submit there can be read, collected or used by other users and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the Personal Information you choose to submit in these forums. These forums may be hosted by BlueLivingIdeas or by one of our third party service providers on BlueLivingIdeas’s behalf.

**You can delete your data**

Your data is yours. You can delete it anytime you want. When you request us to delete your account for the Service, your data will be permanently expunged from our primary production servers and further access to your account will not be possible. We will also promptly disconnect any connection we had established to your Account Information and delete all Account Credentials. However, portions of your data, consisting of aggregate data derived from your Account Information, may remain on our servers indefinitely.

Your data may also remain on a backup server or media. BlueLivingIdeas keeps these backups to ensure our continued ability to provide the Service to you in the event of malfunction or damage to our primary production servers. We reserve the right to use any aggregated or anonymous data derived from or incorporating your Personal Information.

**Communications from us**

We may provide our registered customers with summaries of their Account Information and account alerts or messages by email, phone, or other method of communication provided to BlueLivingIdeas. We may also allow users to subscribe to email newsletters and from time to time may transmit emails promoting BlueLivingIdeas or third party goods or services.

BlueLivingIdeas.com subscribers have the ability to opt-out of receiving our promotional emails and to terminate their newsletter subscriptions by following the instructions in the emails. Opting out in this manner will not end transmission of service-related communications. Additionally, we may use your email address to contact you on behalf of your friends (such as when someone sends you a personal message or notifications from a social network or other website with whom you have registered to receive such notifications).

**Security**

We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet or via mobile device, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

**Third Parties**

We do not rent, share, trade, or sell Personal Information with third parties for their direct marketing purposes. That said, please note the following:

**Service Providers.** Some of the services provided through the Site are provided by third party providers, such as the blog and forum. We may also outsource some of our functions to third parties such as technical support, tracking or reporting functions, payment processing, and other services. We may share information from or about you with these third party providers so that they can perform their services and complete your requests.

**Aggregate Information.** We may share information from and about you with third parties. For example, we may disclose the number of users that have been exposed to or clicked on specific content.

**Investigations**. We may investigate and disclose information from or about you if we have a good faith belief that such investigation or disclosure is (a) reasonably necessary to comply with legal process and law enforcement instructions and orders, such as a search warrant, subpoena, statute, judicial proceeding, or other legal process served on us; (b) helpful to prevent, investigate, or identify possible wrongdoing in connection with the Site; or (c) protect our rights, reputation, property, or that of our users affiliates, or the public.

**Advertising and third party Cookies.** We may allow third parties who provide services relating to advertising to use Cookies in connection with your use of the Site. Through this, they may collect and store the same type of information and use it for the same type of purposes as described for BlueLivingIdeas above, and they may be able to associate the information they collect with other information they have about you from other sources. We do not necessarily have access to or control over the Cookies they use.

**Links.** The Site may contain links to unaffiliated third party websites. Except as set forth herein, we do not share your personal information with them, and are not responsible for their privacy practices. We exercise no control over how your information is stored, maintained or displayed by third parties or on third party sites. Please read the privacy policies of all third party websites. You are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of your Registration Information.

Please act responsibly to maintain the security and confidentiality of your BlueLivingIdeas Registration Information, including your Login ID and Password, as well as Account Credentials for Third Party Sites. You should not provide your BlueLivingIdeas Registration Information to any third party. If you believe that your Registration Information has been stolen or been made known to others, you must contact us immediately at us, but in any event you should change your password immediately via the Service. We are not responsible if someone else accesses your account through Registration Information they have obtained from you or through a violation by you of this Privacy Policy or the BlueLivingIdeas.com Terms of Use.

**Children**

This Site is intended for general audiences and is not directed to Children under 18. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 18. If you become aware that a child has provided us with personal information without parental consent, please contact us. If we become aware that a child under 18 has provided us with personal information without parental consent, we take steps to remove such information and terminate the child’s account.

We post updates on our website whenever there is a change to our Privacy Policy We update this Privacy Policy periodically. The date last revised appears on the Policy. Changes take effect immediately upon posting.

**[Contact us](mailto:hello@bluelivingideas.com) if you have any questions or concerns. **
